# OLENA SHPYLOVA

+380953172190



lshpylova@gmail.com



Ukraine, Kyiv



# **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated and professional QA Engineer with 7 years of experience providing high-level testing. Have experience in Finance, Insurance, Healthcare, Investing domains in Agile environment. Strong experience in agile methodology, and web, back-end testing. Experienced with Defect tracking systems such as Jira, Azure DevOps. Professional experience in designing Test Cases, Test Plans, Check Lists, Test Scripts in Postman, Cypress.

### **EDUCATION**

## NTUU, Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute

Masters Degree in Automation Experimental researches 2013

Masters Degree in Finance and Credits 2009 – 2012

#### **Beetroot Academy**

Business Analyst, 2022

Figma: Wireframes , Draw.io: BPMN and UML; Analysis of requirements to the product; Risks, Communication with development team.

## **SKILLS**

- Strong organizational and timemanagement skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously
- Mentoring, Delegation
- Upper Intermediate English
- Scrum, Kanban
- Decomposition for the tickets
- Postman, Swagger, Json, XML, MS SQL, VS Code, Cypress, Figma, Confluence, Jira, Remote Servers, Notion, Google apps, Git

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## QA Lead, Team Lead

- Project: Web, mobile applications for students(Calaton Academy)
- Stack: Java+Nest.js, React+JS, Rest API
- Tools: Jira, Confluence, Notion, Slack, Cypress, Swagger, Postman, Figma, Google chat, calls, docs, excel...

#### Calaton Academy | 2023 August - Present

- Role Involves in the E2E Product design, Planning and Testing stages, Understanding the Client Requirements, design, functionality.
- Prepare Test Data for the identified test objective in the planning stage.
- Attend meetings regarding the Change Request/Problem Tickets with Development Team, and Product management Team Prepared Test Conditions, Test Cases and Test Summary Report.
- Involve in Customer-related issues and bugs testing.
- Conduct full functional, integration, localization, regression and sanity, smoke testing based on business requirements and design documents.
- Perform Back end Testing-using Swagger, Postman
- Perform Web and Mobile testing
- Perform scrum meetings (Daily, Refinement, Retro, Demo, Planning)
- Mentor new Students for QA Course. Created Studding Plan for course.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Manual QA Engineer, Varteq

May 2022 - Aug 2023

- Project: Web applications for medical organization (Healthcare)
- Stack: React+JavaScript/nodejs serverless/apollo graphgl 95%, ASP.NET Core +Razor pages 5%
- Tools: Azure, Confluence, Visual Code, MS SQL, Jira, X-ray, JS, Cypress, Figma
- Created over 100 test-cases, documentation in confluence: Test Plan, Check List. Articles, Test cases
- Performed regression, smoke, sanity, integration, functional testing, cross-browser testing
- Involved into backend testing using MS SQL
- Requirements analysis, design reviews
- Performed scrum meetings (daily, retro)
- Collaborated closely with development, product management and design teams Wrote autotests with Cypress for regression Cypress+JS (30%)
- Scrum facilitation meetings

#### **QA Engineer, EPAM**

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021

- Performed Functional, Non-Functional, Regression, Integration, Smoke and Sanity, cross-browser testing
- Accurately document defects using a standardized defect tracking system, clearly explaining the issue with the necessary information for developers to replicate and address the problems
- Involved in backend testing using SQL, Restful API Testing: Postman, Swagger; Soap API (XML)
- Worked with OS Linux
- Worked with logs (Kibana, Remote servers)
- Involved to the support session each week
- Automation testing on C#, Selenium, supported existed tests
- Collaborated closely with development, product management teams
- Maintained and updated test cases, test data, and testing documentation as the application evolves, ensuring the QA team's knowledge base is up to date

#### Manual QA Engineer, AltaReturn

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019

Project: Web, mobile applications for investors

Stack: JavaScript, C#

Tools: TFS, MS SQL, Postman, Swagger, Jira, Visual Studio, BrowserStack

- Created and updated more than 200 test-cases
- Performed performance, regression, functional, non-functional, smoke, sanity, API, integration testing
- Created checklists and articles
- Started to write autotests with C#
- Scrum facilitation meetings
- Worked with CRM Microsoft and new built is CRM applications (developed by product company)

#### Manual QA Engineer, Adstream

Jan 2013 - Aug 2015

**Project:** Web Advertising Agency

Stack: Java, JS, MS SQL

- Performed Functional, Non-Functional, Regression, Integration, Smoke and Sanity, cross-browser testing
- Involved in backend testing using SQL, Swagger, Postman
- API Testing: Postman
- · Worked with OS Linux
- Worked with logs (Remote servers)